Guide to the World Student Christian Federation Records
Yale University Divinity School Library
- B United States, Series XI
  - B500: Organized Lines of Work and Study/ General Methods
    - B540: Mission study and service
      - B549: History of the student missionary movement
        - B549.6: Conferences
          - B549.67: Sundry conferences (SVM)
            - Detroit international convention -- press reports, 1894 (Box 72, Folder 586)
            - India at Cleveland SVM International Conference, 1898 (Box 72, Folder 587)
            - Cleveland SVM Convention press reports, 1898 (Box 72, Folder 587)
            - Ontario SVM Convention Press reports, 1902 (Box 72, Folder 587)
            - Nashville SVM Convention Press reports, 1906 (Box 73, Folder 588-590)
            - Kansas City SVM convention Press reports, 1914 (Box 73, Folder 591)
          - B549.68: Programs for SVM Conventions
            - Cleveland, 1891, 1898 (Box 73, Folder 592)
            - Rochester, 1910 (Box 73, Folder 592)
          - B549.69 Conference reports, minutes, agenda
            - Report re. Chicago convention of American Interseminary Missionary Alliance, 1882 (Box 73, Folder 593)
            - Proceedings of Chicago convention of American Interseminary Missionary Alliance, 1896 (Box 73, Folder 593)
            - SVM Board Secretary Conference in Cleveland, 1898 (Box 73, Folder 593)
            - SVM representatives conference -- agenda, minutes, 1905 (Box 73, Folder 593)
            - Conference on Preparation of Ordained Missionaries, Board of Missionary Preparation, 1914 (Box 73, Folder 593)
        - B549.7: Miscellaneous
          - Notes on A New Programme For Missions (Box 73, Folder 594)
          - Statement re. need of persons for work in foreign countries (Box 73, Folder 594)
    - B550: Social study and service.
      - General
        - B550.1: Bibliography
          - Bibliography of College, Social, and University Settlements (Box 74, Folder 595)
        - B550.3: Items listed as B550
          - Butler. The Social Service Committee, 1912 (Box 74, Folder 595)
          - Butler: Christian Living in Terms of Service, 1916 (Box 74, Folder 595)
          - Fox. An Idea That Grew, 1920 (Box 74, Folder 595)
          - King. The Four Parties to Industry, 1919 (Box 74, Folder 595)
          - Lichty. Common Service in the Student Field (Box 74, Folder 595)
          - Sanford. The Social Department (Box 74, Folder 595)
          - Trawick. Social Investigation, 1907 (Box 74, Folder 595)
          - Papers re. Summer vacation work, 1892, n.d. (Box 74, Folder 596)
          - Various articles re. the Church in the world (Box 74, Folder 596)
      - B551: Social study. Methods and organization
        - B551.1: Prospectus
          - Challenge of American Social Problems to College Men and Women, 1913-1914 (Box 74, Folder 597)
        - B551.2: Leadership
          - Drew. Group Leadership, 1923 (Box 74, Folder 597)
          - Elliott. The Why and How of Group Discussion, 1923 (Box 74, Folder 597)
      - B552: Textbooks
        - Items listed in card catalogue, 1906-1922 (Box 74, Folder 598, 599)
      - B554 Social service. Obligations as to community service implied in Christianity and resting upon the church-- For items listed as B554, see B554.3
        - B554.1 Enlistment of voluntary service
          - Community Service, 1912 (Box 74, Folder 600)
          - The Challenge of American Social Problem to College Men and Women, 1913-1914 (Box 74, Folder 600)
          - Volunteer Social Service by College Men, 1914 (Box 74, Folder 600)
          - How to Work Out a Service Program (Box 74, Folder 600)
          - How May College Women Be Found for Volunteer Service?, 1913 (Box 74, Folder 600)
          - The College Man's Opportunity (Box 74, Folder 600)
          - Various papers re. recruitment (Box 74, Folder 600)
        - B554.2:Enlistment of Christian students in professions promotive of community betterment
          - Burton. An Open Letter to A Christian Young Man in College (Box 74, Folder 601)
          - Henderson. Callings., 1892 (Box 74, Folder 601)
          - Ober/Williams. A Commanding Opportunity for a Life Investment, 1903 (Box 74, Folder 601)
          - Palmer. Christianity and the Law, 1871 (Box 74, Folder 601)
          - Pope. Attractions of the Ministry (Box 74, Folder 601)
        - B554.3: Items listed as B554
          - King. Leaders of Tomorrow (Box 74, Folder 602)
          - Ward. Social Duties in War Time, 1917 (Box 74, Folder 602)
          - Social Needs and the Colleges, 1914 (Box 74, Folder 602)
          - Salaried Positions For Men in Social Work, 1913 (Box 74, Folder 602)
          - China in 1923 (Box 74, Folder 602)
          - Papers re. College Summer Service Group, 1920,1923 (Box 74, Folder 602)
      - B555A: Institutions and Organizations for Social Effort on behalf of Students
        - Various pamphlets/leaflets re. Student Friendship War Fund -- WWI (Box 74, Folder 603)
        - Leaflets re. German Students Cooperative Association (Box 74, Folder 603)
        - Article re. POW's in WWI (Box 74, Folder 603)
      - B555B Institutions and Organizations for Social Effort by Students
        - B555B.2: For People in Small Towns and country
          - Pamphlets re. Eight Week Clubs, YWCA (Box 75, Folder 604)
          - Pamphlets re. citizenship/leadership, YWCA (Box 75, Folder 605)
          - Papers re. rural service, YWCA (Box 75, Folder 605)
        - B555B.3 For Armed Forces
          - The Christian Witness in War (Box 75, Folder 606)
          - Students of America for the Students in European War Prisons (Box 75, Folder 606)
      - B556 Social morality-- For items listed as B556, see B556.3
        - B556.1 Economic, political, and moral conditions of women
          - Fox. When Labor Goes to School, 1920 (Box 75, Folder 607)
          - Friedmann. How to Begin -- Organization, 1921 (Box 75, Folder 607)
          - idem. The Industrial Club and its Program, 1918 (Box 75, Folder 607)
          - idem. The Federation -- an Industrial Movement, 1920 (Box 75, Folder 607)
          - Hayton. Unemployment, 1922 (Box 75, Folder 607)
          - Leigh, M. The New Coming of Age, 1920 (Box 75, Folder 608)
          - Leigh, R. More Than the Vote, 1920 (Box 75, Folder 608)
          - idem. A Spur to the Reluctant Voter, 1920 (Box 75, Folder 608)
          - Master. Health and the Women's Movement, 1916 (Box 75, Folder 608)
          - Taylor. Present Conditions of Women (Box 75, Folder 608)
          - Leaflets/outlines re. Students and Work (Box 75, Folder 608)
        - B556.2 Sex education
          - Exner. Friend or Enemy, 1917 (Box 75, Folder 609)
          - idem. Problems and Principles of Sex Education, 1915 (Box 75, Folder 609)
          - Gray. Men, Women and God (Box 75, Folder 609)
          - Willson. The Social Evil in University Life, 1904 (Box 75, Folder 609)
          - Health and the Hygiene of Sex, 1911 (Box 75, Folder 609)
        - B556.3 Items listed as B556
          - Report: Social Morality from the Christian Standpoint, 1913 (Box 75, Folder 610)
          - Mott's personal notes re. social purity (Box 75, Folder 610)
    - B560 Entertainment. Athletics. Hygiene
      - Dabb. The Social Committee, 1912 (Box 75, Folder 611)
      - Edgar. The Wayside Piper, 1915 (Box 75, Folder 611)
      - Miller. The Christmas Story, 1915 (Box 75, Folder 611)
      - Santmyer. The Spirit of Sisterhood, 1915 (Box 75, Folder 611)
      - Thoburn. The Ministering of the Gift, 1913 (Box 75, Folder 611)
      - Health Inventory (Box 75, Folder 612)
      - The Drama of Esther, 1917 (Box 75, Folder 612)
      - The Student's Part in the National Jubilee, 1915 (Box 75, Folder 612)
      - Girls of Yesterday and Today, 1915 (Box 75, Folder 612)
      - The Aftermath, 1914 (Box 75, Folder 612)
      - The Social and Recreation Committee (Box 75, Folder 612)
    - B570 Business and publicity. Appeals for financial aid.
      - idem. Association Finance, 1915 (Box 76, Folder 613)
      - Groner. An Adequate Financial Policy (Box 76, Folder 613)
      - Helmer. The Finance Committee of a School or College Association, 1916 (Box 76, Folder 613)
      - Leonard. The Finances of the College Association, 1895 (Box 76, Folder 613)
      - Mott. The Largest Voluntary Offering in History (Box 76, Folder 613)
      - Paxson. The Finance Committee of Student YWCA (Box 76, Folder 613)
      - Sanford. The Finance Department, 1907 (Box 76, Folder 613)
      - United Student Christian Council - Promotion, finances, 1954 (Box 293, Folder 2671)
      - YWCA National Budget, 1914 (Box 76, Folder 614)
      - YMCA general balance sheets and gross financial operations, 1922-1923 (Box 76, Folder 614)
      - YWCA leaflets re. student dollars/finances, 1914,n.d. (Box 76, Folder 615)
      - YMCA Appeal for support (Box 76, Folder 615)
      - YWCA Manual of Finance, 1922 (Box 76, Folder 615)
      - How Shall I Spend My Money? (Box 76, Folder 615)
  - B600 Associations in Individual Institutions or among Special Classes of Students
    - General
      - B600.2: Statistics of Professional Colleges, etc., in Metropolitan Areas, 1895-1898 (Box 76, Folder 616)
    - B610 Colleges, universities and student departments of metropolitan and state associations
      - Re. specific institututions
        - Material re. Univ. of Michigan and students' religious lives (Box 76, Folder 616)
        - Material re. University of Hawaii, 1925-1927 (Box 293, Folder 2676)
        - Scrapbook documenting Christian Association of Cornell University, 1898 (Box 315, Folder 1)
        - Materials re. college students and the YMCA, 1920-1923 (Box 76, Folder 616)
        - B610.01 Bibliography: Nucleus for the Library of Madison Hall, University of Virginia, 1905 (Box 76, Folder 617)
        - B610.3 Cards and blanks: Phillips Brooks House Associations (Box 76, Folder 617)
        - B610.3 Cards and blanks: Philadelphian Society (Box 76, Folder 617)
        - B610.3 Cards and blanks: Univ. of Pennsylvania Christian Associations (Box 76, Folder 617)
      - B611 Student Movements
        - Leaflets re. the Students' Movement (Box 76, Folder 617)
        - Leaflets re. various YMCA college departments (Box 76, Folder 617)
        - Leaflet by Univ. of Penn. Christian Association (Box 76, Folder 617)
        - B611.21 Student Achievements Work at Phillips Brooks House (Box 76, Folder 617)
        - B611.25 Christian Associations: Materials re. Yale and Cornell Christian Associations, 1897,1899,1900 (Box 76, Folder 617)
      - B612 Buildings and property
        - Press releases re. YMCA and various associations' property (Box 76, Folder 618)
        - Materials re. various buildings on college campuses (Box 76, Folder 619, 620)
      - B613 Organization, incorporation
        - University Christian Mission Manual, n.d. (Box 293, Folder 2677)
        - B613.1 Constitution and membership
          - Constitutions of various Christian Associations at various campuses, 1859-1908 (Box 76, Folder 621)
        - B613.3 Membership
          - B613.32 Basis: Letters re. membership in various Christian Associations at various campuses (Box 76, Folder 622)
      - B614 _________
        - B614.1: Materials re.Christian Associations at Yale (Box 76, Folder 622)
      - B615 Organized lines of work and study
        - Christianity and the College Man, 1922 (Box 77, Folder 623)
        - Some Actual Methods of Student Christian Work, 1908 (Box 77, Folder 623)
        - B615.004 Calendars: Calendars for Christian meetings at Yale and Univ. of Michigan, 1886-1887 (Box 77, Folder 623)
        - B615.1 Evangelistic and philanthropic work among students
          - Sunday Evening Talks to Yale Undergraduates, 1899 (Box 77, Folder 624)
          - University Christian Mission on various campuses (Box 77, Folder 624)
          - Religious Emphasis Week, 1949-1957 (Box 293, Folder 2678)
          - Miscellaneous Articles, 1936-1952 (Box 293, Folder 2679)
          - B615.12 Personal workers' texts
            - Outline of Purdue Faculty Personal Workers Class (Box 77, Folder 624)
            - Address to YMCA by R. McKim, 1875 (Box 77, Folder 624)
            - Address to YMCA by W. Marquess, 1885 (Box 77, Folder 624)
            - An Appeal to the Churches, SVM, 1887 (Box 77, Folder 624)
        - B615.2 Devotional and inspirational
          - B615.221 Calls to prayer: From Pennsylvania Univ, 1895 (Box 77, Folder 624)
          - B615.222 Prayer cycles: Purdue YMCA (Box 77, Folder 624)
          - B615.24 Univ. of Chicago YMCA/YWCA: Announcements of World Problems Forum, 1919 (Box 77, Folder 625)
          - YMCA student demonstration for world brotherhood in Cairo, 1919 (Box 77, Folder 625)
        - B615.3 Bible study
          - B615.31 Bible study: YMCA Bible study in New York City colleges (Box 77, Folder 625)
          - B615.311 University Bible study: Yale and Cornell, 1890's (Box 77, Folder 625)
          - B615.313 Christian Association Bible study: Harvard Univ, 1904 (Box 77, Folder 625)
          - B615.313 Christian Association Bible study: United Christian Youth Mvt.: "Daily Devotions for Young People", 1948 (Box 293, Folder 2680)
          - B615.32 Bible study: Yale and Harvard Bible studies, 1900-1904 (Box 77, Folder 626)
          - B615.33 Univ. of Pennsylvania Bible study: Leaflets (Box 77, Folder 626)
        - B615.4 Mission study and service
          - Univ. of Chicago YMCA resume of activities, 1919 (Box 77, Folder 626)
          - B615.411 Programs: Mission study at Johns Hopkins, 1904-1905 (Box 77, Folder 626)
          - B615.44 Bulletins: American Univ. at Cairo bulletin, 1919 (Box 77, Folder 626)
          - B615.444 Yale Missionary Band: General materials, press notices, report letters, 1898-1899 (Box 77, Folder 627)
          - B615.47 Yale in China: A Visit to Yale In China, 1920 (Box 77, Folder 628)
          - Yale's Contribution to Foreign Missions, 1701-1901 (Box 77, Folder 628)
          - Letters from Princeton Volunteers of SVMFM, 1888 (Box 77, Folder 628)
          - Reports re. the Harvard Mission, 1907,1911,1922 (Box 77, Folder 628)
          - Report re. Yale In China, 1917,1918 (Box 77, Folder 628)
          - Portfolios re. Yale in China, 1919,1920 (Box 77, Folder 629)
          - Quarterlies re. Yale in China, 1879 (Box 77, Folder 629)
        - B615.5 Social study and service
          - Pamphlets re. Christian activity at Yale (Box 77, Folder 629)
          - Harvard Social Service Commission, 1908,1909 (Box 77, Folder 629)
          - B615.541 YMCA social work: Pamphlets re. social/reli-gious work in New York City (Box 77, Folder 629)
          - B615.551 Summer camps: Univ. of Penn. Christian Settlement and summer camps, 1904 (Box 77, Folder 629)
          - B615.554 YWCA/YMCA: List of YWCA student centers in New York City, 1920 (Box 77, Folder 630)
          - B615.554 YWCA/YMCA: YMCA map of college and university centers in New York City, 1920 (Box 77, Folder 630)
        - B615.7 Finances
          - Cornell Univ. Christian Association financial appeals, 1904 (Box 77, Folder 630)
        - B615.8 Student handbooks by Christian Associations
          - Smith, 1898-1899 (Box 77, Folder 631)
          - Harvard, 1904-1905 (Box 77, Folder 631)
          - Univ. of Pennsylvania, 1904 (Box 77, Folder 631)
          - Tulane (Box 77, Folder 631)
          - Cincinnati (city of) (Box 77, Folder 631)
      - B619 History
        - Christian activity at Yale (Box 78, Folder 632)
        - Michigan Univ. SCA, 1858-1908 (Box 78, Folder 632)
        - History of the Founding of First YMCA among students at Univ. of Virginia, 1908 (Box 78, Folder 632)
        - The Origin of a Great Movement (Box 78, Folder 632)
        - Proposed outline re. Yale Christian Associations (Box 78, Folder ????)
        - B619.1 Reports
          - Summary report re. American Student Friendship Pilgrimage to Europe, 1922 (Box 78, Folder 633)
          - Philadelphian Society of Princeton, 1902-1904 (Box 78, Folder 633)
          - Phillips Brooks House, Harvard, 1906-1908 (Box 78, Folder 633)
          - Association Record, Univ. of Virginia, 1903-1910 (Box 78, Folder 634)
          - Cornell Christian Association, 1903-1904, 1907-1908 (Box 78, Folder 635)
          - Univ. of Pennsylvania Christian Association, 1904 (Box 78, Folder 635)
          - Univ. of Michigan Christian Association, 1887 (Box 78, Folder 635)
          - YMCA of New York City, 1893-1894, 1898,1899, 1912, 1914 (Box 78, Folder 636)
          - YMCA of Chicago, 1899-1900 (Box 78, Folder 637)
          - Univ. of Illinois YMCA, 1898-1899, 1903-1904 (Box 78, Folder 637)
          - Univ. of California YMCA, 1900 (Box 78, Folder 637)
          - Brown YMCA, 1899-1900, 1902-1903 (Box 78, Folder 637)
          - Boston YMCA, 1899-1900 (Box 78, Folder 637)
          - Mt. Holyoke YWCA, 1903-1904 (Box 78, Folder 637)
          - B619.11 Statistical/progress reports
            - Univ. of Illinois YMCA, 1903-1904 (Box 78, Folder 638)
            - Cornell Christian Association, 1902-1903 (Box 78, Folder 638)
            - Purdue YMCA, 1900 (Box 78, Folder 638)
            - Univ. of Michigan YMCA, 1903-1904 (Box 78, Folder 638)
          - B619.12 Official's reports, YMCA
            - Northwestern, 1898-1899 (Box 78, Folder 638)
            - Univ. of Minnesota, 1901 (Box 78, Folder 638)
            - Indiana Univ (Box 78, Folder 638)
            - Chicago (city), 1900 (Box 78, Folder 638)
        - B619.5 Periodicals -- Christian Association Bulletins
          - Cornell, 1888-1897 (Box 79, Folder 639)
          - Univ. of Michigan, 1887-1896 (Box 79, Folder 639a)
          - Johns Hopkins, YMCA, 1890-1891 (Box 79, Folder 639b)
          - Miscellaneous Christian Assn. Bulletins, 1948-1953 (Box 293, Folder 2681)
    - B620 Professional Schools
      - B621 Theological
        - B621.58 Handbooks: McCormick Theological Seminary, 1897-1898 (Box 80, Folder 640)
      - B622 Medical (reports)
        - The P S Club, New York City YMCA, 1922 (Box 80, Folder 640)
        - History and first report of the College of Physicians and Surgeons, Columbia, 1896 (Box 80, Folder 640)
        - Baltimore Medical College, 1899-1900 (Box 80, Folder 640)
    - B630 Secondary Schools
      - YMCA
        - B639.6 YMCA Conferences for work with boys
          - B639.61 Bulletins: Portschach, Austria, 1923 (Box 80, Folder 641)
          - B639.61 Bulletins: Estes Park, Colorado, 1925 (Box 80, Folder 641)
          - B639.68 Programs: Estes Park, Colorado, 1925 (Box 80, Folder 641)
          - B639.69 Resolutions, reports: Portschach, Austria, 1923 (Box 80, Folder 641)
    - B640 Schools for blacks
      - Negro Men Students and the Christian Youth Movement (Box 80, Folder 642)
    - B660 Associations among special classes
      - B662: Women students
        - YWCA. Pamphlets and constitutions., 1907-1923 (Box 310, Folder 2919)
      - B664 Auxiliary associations of non-students
        - Religious and Philanthropic Work Outside the college, 1906 (Box 80, Folder 642)
    - B690 Foreign Students
      - General
        - Resolutions of Filipino Students Federation, 1922 (Box 80, Folder 643)
        - Task and prospects of YMCA in Poland, 1923 (Box 80, Folder 643)
        - An Occasional Leaflet, YMCA in China, 1909 (Box 80, Folder 643)
        - Ideals and Activities of the Chinese Students' Christian Association in North America, 1913 (Box 80, Folder 643)
        - Directory of Japanese students in North America and Hawaii, 1927-1928 (Box 80, Folder 643)
        - What Do You Say, America? (Box 80, Folder 643)
        - Sundry documents on Commission on Friendly Relations with Foreign Students, c.1922 (Box 80, Folder 644)
        - Materials re. foreign women students in U.S., 1922-1923 (Box 80, Folder 644)
        - Work among women foreign students in U.S., 1919-1920 (Box 80, Folder 644)
        - B693.1 Constitutions: Japanese Christian Students' Union of America, 1899? (Box 80, Folder 645)
        - B693.1 Constitutions: Chinese Students' Christian Association in North America (Box 80, Folder 645)
        - B695.191 Work of foreign students - Service, Chinese (Box 80, Folder 645)
        - B696.4969 China: Chinese Students and China's Religious Awakening (Box 80, Folder 645)
        - B696.7 Conferences: Report of Silver Bay Student Conference, New York, 1922 (Box 80, Folder 645)
      - B697 Appeals
        - An appeal to members of the Eastern Department, 1923 (Box 80, Folder 645)
      - B699 ______________
        - B699.1 Chinese Students Christian Association in North America (See also: RG13)
          - Annual reports, 1911-1913 (Box 80, Folder 646)
          - Year book, 1925 (Box 80, Folder 646)
          - Report re. Midwest conference (Box 80, Folder 646)
          - Picture portfolios, 1923-1924 (Box 80, Folder 647)
        - B699.2 Japanese Christian Students Union of America
          - Various committee reports and letters, 1900-1904 (Box 80, Folder 648)
        - B699.5 Various Christian Movement Publications
          - "Russian Student", by Russian Students' Christian Association, 1923 (Box 80, Folder 650)
          - "Christian China", by Chinese Students' Christian Association, 1927 (Box 80, Folder 650)
          - CSCA General Secretary's monthly reports, 1910-1914 (Box 81, Folder 651, 652)
  - B700 Student Life in General Outside the Federation
    - General
      - Reports
        - Christian Activity at Yale series (Box 81, Folder 653)
        - American Univ. Union in Europe, 1918 (Box 81, Folder 653)
        - Address re. Rutgers graduates in Japan, 1916 (Box 81, Folder 653)
        - Harvard's Better Self, 1890 (Box 81, Folder 653)
        - Picture portfolio re. the Houston Club at Univ. of Pennsylvania (Box 81, Folder 654)
        - News clippings re. religious life at Harvard and Univ. of Nebraska, 1904 (Box 81, Folder 654)
        - Notes re. religious societies among students before YMCA (Box 81, Folder 654)
        - Plan of the Federation, 1905 (Box 81, Folder 654)
        - Cornell Alumni News, 1911 (Box 81, Folder 654)
      - B701 Bibliography
        - Vassar College Bulletin: List of References on college and University Government and Administration, 1921 (Box 81, Folder 655)
      - B702 University catalogs. Educational bulletins
        - McBurney School, 1923 (Box 81, Folder 655)
        - The College at Springfield, 655 (Box 81, Folder 655)
        - Constantinople Woman's College, 1921-1922 (Box 81, Folder 656)
        - General Education Board annual report, 1918-1919 (Box 81, Folder 656)
        - International Sunday School Council of Religious Education, Report of Committee on Education, 1922 (Box 81, Folder 656)
        - Presentation re. Medical education in the U.S., 1920 (Box 81, Folder 657)
        - Skill and Scholarship as Ideals in Medical Graduate Education, 1919 (Box 81, Folder 657)
        - Colorado Fuel Iron Company Industrial Bulletin: Our High School and College Students (Box 81, Folder 657)
        - Bureau of Education Bulletin, 1909,1915 (Box 81, Folder 658)
        - Institute of International Education Bulletins, 1920-1927 (Box 81, Folder 657)
      - B703 Service cards
        - Declaration card for student recruits to the Christian ministry (Box 82, Folder 660)
    - B710 Other organizations of students or other classes having interests similar to those of the Federation
      - Chinese National Union pamphlets, 1911,1912 (Box 82, Folder 660)
      - St. Paul's Society, Harvard (Box 82, Folder 660)
      - Students Recruits Movement, pamphlets, 1907 (Box 82, Folder 660)
      - B712 Chinese Students Alliance in the U.S. Pamphlets re. membership, 1919-1920 (Box 82, Folder 660)
      - B713.32 Bryn Mawr League for the Service of Christ: Card re. membership (Box 82, Folder 660)
    - B750 Organized lines of work and study